♪～
～♪
The Legacy
Granny Chiyo...
（春野はるのサクラ）チヨバア様
What are you trying to do?
（うずまきナルト）
何をしようってんだ？
（日向ひゅうがネジ）医療忍術？ いや…
Medical Ninjutsu...?
No...
私たちのやるべきことは
終わりました
We did what we had to do.
すぐにでも里に戻って解毒しないと
Now, if we don't hurry back
to the Village Hidden in the Sand
and give you an antidote...
（チヨ）ハア ハア…
それよりも わしにはまだ
More important than that,
there is...something...
やるべきことがある
that I still...must do.
（サクラ）チヨバア様が言っていたの
このこと？
This is what Granny Chiyo
was talking about...
Is that...?
（マイト･ガイ）あれは…
（はたけカカシ）ああ
Yeah...
あっ 何をしてんだってばよ
Hey, what are you doing?!
うっ…
（サクラ）チヨバア様は
自分の命と引き換えに…
Granny Chiyo...
in exchange for her own life...
（チヨ）うう…
サクラちゃ…
Sakura...
我愛羅があら君を生き返らせる
She's going to bring
Gaara back to life!
（ナルト）はっ！
生き返らせる？
Bring him back to life...
そんなこと
ほんとに できんのか？
Is such a thing...
really possible?
（サクラ）この術は
（ナルト）あっ
This Jutsu...
チヨバア様だけの特別な術
is a special Jutsu that
only Granny Chiyo possesses...
Really?!
そうなのか？
（ネジ）そんな都合のいい術が
あるはずはない
There's no way that such
an extraordinary Jutsu could exist...
（ネジ）あのチャクラの流れ
That Chakra flow...
おそらく…
No doubt...
（カカシ）それ相応のリスクを伴う
It is accompanied by
a considerable risk...
（チヨ）うわっ
うう…
クソ…
Damn...!
チャクラが足りぬ　ううっ
I don't have enough Chakra...
ううっ ハア…
ハア ハア…
ハア… ああ クソ…
Damn...
ハア ハア…　ううっ？
You can use my Chakra!
俺のチャクラ使ってくれってばよ
それって できるか？
バアちゃん
Would that be possible?
Granny...
ハア…
（カカシ）我愛羅君は
あいつと同じ人柱力じんちゅうりきです
Gaara is a Jinchuriki,
just like he is.
砂隠すながくれにいるどんな者よりも
ナルトは彼の気持ちが分かってしまう
More than anyone in
the Hidden Sand Village,
Naruto knows how Gaara feels.
人柱力が どんな扱いを受けてきたか
After all, the Jinchuriki has been
treated the same way in every village...
（チヨ）ハア…
（カカシ）それはどの里においても
大差はありませんからね
だからこそ
助けずにはいられないんですよ
That's exactly why he feels
like he has to save Gaara.
It doesn't make any difference to him
木こノ葉はだとか砂だとか
if he's from the Leaf or the Sand.
あいつにとっては そんなこと
どうでもいいことなんでしょう
（チヨ）わしの手の上に
お前の手を重ねろ
Place your hand on top of mine.
（ナルト）う…
うん
Naruto...
（サクラ）ナルト
くっ… ううっ
Naruto's dream is
to become the Hokage...
（カカシ）ナルトの夢は
火影ほかげになることなんですが
He was frustrated when he heard
that Gaara had become the Kazekage.
彼が風影かぜかげになったと聞いて
悔しがっていました
ですが その反面それを心から
喜び祝福していたのもナルトなんです
But at the same time,
he was also very happy for Gaara
from the bottom of his heart.
ナルトには
不思議な力があるんですよ
Naruto has a mysterious power...
くっ…
（カカシ）あいつは
交わす言葉は少なくても
However small the words he exchanges,
he makes friends immediately...
誰とでも すぐ友達に
なってしまうんです
with everyone he meets...
（チヨ）
くだらぬ年寄りどもがつくった
この忍の世界に
Amidst this Shinobi world created
by us foolish old people...
お前のようなヤツが
現れてくれてうれしい
I am glad that a person
like you showed up...
かつて わしのしてきたことは
間違いばかりじゃった
The things I did in the past
were nothing but mistakes...
しかし 最後になって
But...in my last hour,
正しいことが やっとできそうじゃ
it seems I shall finally be able
to do the right thing.
砂と
The Village Hidden in the Sand and ...
the Village Hidden in the Leaves.
木ノ葉
これからの未来は
The future is likely to be different
from the way things were in our time...
わしらのときとは
違ったものになろう
カカシの言っていた
お前の不思議な力
Your mysterious power
that Kakashi spoke of...
その力が未来を
大きく変えるじゃろう
That power is likely to
alter the future greatly...
今までにない火影になってな
when you become a Hokage
like none before...
そしてサクラ
And you, Sakura...!
はい
Yes...
（チヨ）
今度は死にかけのババアではなく
Next time, help the person
you cherish most...
not an old lady with
one foot in the grave...
自分の大切に思う者を助けてやれ
お前は わしとよく似ておろう
You are very much like me...
男気を持ち合わせとる女は
そうおらんからな
There are not many women
who have a man's courage...
お前は師匠を超える
くノ一になるじゃろう
You will probably become
a Kunoichi who surpasses her master...
ナルトよ ババアからのお願いじゃ
Naruto, this old lady has
a favor to ask you...
（ナルト）ん？
（チヨ）お前は我愛羅の痛みを
知ってやることができる唯一の存在じゃ
You are the one and only person
who is capable of knowing
the extent of Gaara's pain...
我愛羅もお前の痛みを知っておる
And Gaara knows your pain, too...
我愛羅を助けてやってくれ
Please...help Gaara...
（ナルト）我愛羅…
Gaara!
Gaara...!
我愛羅！
（我愛羅）誰だ？
誰を… 呼んでる？
Who are you...calling...?
誰だ？
Whose is it...? This hand...
この手…
なんだ また俺の手か
Oh... It's just my hand again...
俺の手…
My hand...
俺…
Me...?
Who am I...?
俺とは誰だ？
I...
俺…
I am...
俺は…
我愛羅…
Gaara...
Naruto...
（我愛羅）ナルト…
う…
これは…
This is...
お前を助けるために
みんな走ってたんだってばよ
Everyone came running to help you.
（マツリ）我愛羅様 大丈夫ですか？
Lord Gaara!
Are you all right?!
あ…
ああ… やった！
- Yes!
- Hurrah!
（砂すなの里さとの忍たち）
ハハハ… よかった
Thank heavens...
That's great!
（砂の里の忍）うっ うう…
おっ ああ…
世話 かけやがって
Putting us to all this trouble!
Good grief.
（カンクロウ）全くだ
心配かけやがる弟じゃんよ
You're such a bothersome little brother,
making us worry like that.
What's with you guys...
acting arrogant like that?!
（テマリ）なんだお前ら 偉そうに
Gaara is the Kazekage, you know.
我愛羅は風影なんだぞ ふんっ
Don't be so disrespectful!
生意気な口きいてんな！
You're nothing but subordinates!
この下っ端ども！
うう…
Gaara... How do you feel?
（テマリ）我愛羅 気分はどうだ？
（我愛羅）うっ
うう…
急に動かないほうがいい
You shouldn't try to
get up so quickly.
体の硬直が まだ完全には
解けてないからな
Your body hasn't completely healed.
うっ
（砂の里の忍）くっ うう…
よかった 風影様
Thank heavens...!
I thought Lord Kazekage...
might really die...
ほんとに死んじゃうかと…
（たたかれる音）
（砂の里の忍）痛いてっ！
There's no way that Lord Gaara
would kick the bucket that easily!
我愛羅様が そう簡単に
くたばるわけないでしょ
ううっ
我愛羅様は無口でクールで
強くて かっこよくてエリートで
Gaara is reserved, cool,
strong, handsome, an elite, and...
（砂の里の忍）
そうそう それでいて
どことなく かわいくって
Yes, yes, but he's still kind
of cute somehow...
And yet, he is the Kazekage...
それなのに風影様で
（たたく音）
（砂の里の忍）だあ…
This time, I'll show them for sure...
that I can protect Lord Gaara in a crisis!
我愛羅様の危機は
私が防いでみせます　今度こそ！
No, I will!
（砂の里の忍）いや 私が
（マツリ）私よ
I will!
（マツリ）いや… 我愛羅様～
（砂の里の忍）どけよ 下っ端
Lord Gaara!
Out of the way, underling!
（ナルト）おお… 痛い
ぐっ
そういや俺ってば
まだ下忍げにんだってばよ
Come to think of it,
I am still a Genin.
（カンクロウ）そう落ち込むな
Don't feel so depressed.
女ってのはエリート志向で
クールなのに弱いって
It's a well known fact that women
have a weakness for the cool, elite type.
相場は決まってんじゃん
（ナルト）いや なんかシカマルも
そんなようなこと言ってたっけか
I think Shikamaru was saying
something like that too...
ふ～ん
（我愛羅）あいつは
俺と同じ苦しみを知っていた
He has known the same suffering
I have...
And he has taught me that
そして 生きる道を変えることが
できることを教えてくれた
it is possible to change
one's path in life...
俺もいつか 誰からも必要とされる
存在になりたい
I, too, want to become the kind of man
that everyone looks up to...
Thank you... Naruto!
（カンクロウ）ありがとよ ナルト
あ…
If you're going to say that,
それを言うなら俺にじゃなく
バアちゃんにだ
you should say it to the old lady, not me...
She saved Gaara with
an incredible Medical Ninjutsu...
我愛羅を すごい医療忍術で
助けてくれた
She got tired out,
so she's sleeping now, but...
今は疲れて寝ちゃったけど
バアちゃんも里に帰ったら元気に…
When the old lady gets back
to the village, she'll get well again...
No, you're wrong...
（カンクロウ）いや 違う
ん？
（カンクロウ）
チヨバアは あの術を…
Granny Chiyo used  that Jutsu...
What do you mean I'm wrong?
違うって 何が？
I...
（マツリたち）私が
（マツリ）あ… うん？
She wasn't just using Medical Ninjutsu...
（カンクロウ）
医療忍術なんかじゃない
転生忍術だ
She used the Reanimation Ninjutsu.
Granny Chiyo is dead.
チヨバアは死んだんだ
Reanimation Ninjutsu?
（テンテン）転生忍術？
Wh- What do you mean by that?
な… どういうことだってばよ
It's a Ninjutsu that allows you
自分の命と引き換えに
死んだ者をすら生き返らせる忍術
to bring a dead person back to life
in exchange for your own...
あっ！
It can't be...!
そんな…
As I thought...
（ネジ）やはり…
（ロック･リー）ガイ先生
Guy Sensei...
うん
（カンクロウ）
砂の傀儡くぐつ部隊でいっとき
At one time, in the Sand Puppet Unit,
傀儡に生命を与える術を
研究開発しようとしていた
they were doing research to develop
a Jutsu that could bring puppets to life.
チヨバアが先頭に立ってな
Granny Chiyo headed up
the project...
あっ
They succeeded in developing
the Jutsu in theory,
術の理論は開発できたが
but midway, they decided
that the risks were too great.
途中 術のリスクが
あまりにも大きいってことで
Before it reached the stage
of human experiments,
人体実験の前に禁術に指定され
封印された術だ
it was designated as a Forbidden Jutsu
and it was sealed.
（チヨ）
くだらぬ年寄りどもがつくった
この忍の世界に
Amidst this Shinobi world created
by us foolish old people...
I am glad that a person
like you showed up...
お前のようなヤツが
現れてくれてうれしい
かつて わしのしてきたことは
間違いばかりじゃった
The things I did in the past
were nothing but mistakes...
But in my last hour,
しかし 最後の最後になって
正しいことが やっとできそうじゃ
it seems I shall finally be able
to do the right thing...
The Village Hidden in the Sand
and the Village Hidden in the Leaves...
砂と木ノ葉… これからの未来は
The future to come is
likely to be different
わしらのときとは
違ったものになろう
from the way things were
in our time...
（ナルト）あ…
（チヨ）カカシの言っていた
お前の不思議な力
Your mysterious power
that Kakashi spoke of...
その力が未来を
大きく変えるじゃろう
That power is likely to
alter the future greatly...
when you become a Hokage
like none before...
今までにない火影になってな
I was only pretending to be dead.
な～んてな　死んだふり～
アハ アヒヒ… アハハ…
（エビゾウ）…てな
Just like that.
今にも笑い出しそうな
そんな安らかな顔をしておるよ
She looks as if she could start
laughing at any minute.
Her face looks so...peaceful...
Yes...
（サクラ）はい…
はい！
Naruto, you are a mysterious one,
after all.
（テマリ）ナルト やっぱり
お前は不思議なヤツだな
You have the power to change people.
お前には人を変えていく力がある
チヨバア様は里の未来など
どうでもいいといつも言っていた
Granny Chiyo always used to say
she didn't care about the village's future...
我愛羅のために こんなことを
するような人じゃなかった
She was not the kind of person
to do such a thing for Gaara.
（カカシ）チヨバア様は
我愛羅君とお前に未来を託した
Granny Chiyo entrusted the future
to Gaara and you...
忍らしい立派な最期だ
（ナルト）うん
三代目のじいちゃんと同じだ
（カカシ）そうだな
（ナルト）うん バアちゃんの想おもい
今なら はっきり分かるってばよ
あっ！ 我愛羅様
いい…
うっ
皆 チヨバア様に祈りを
（サクラ）チヨバア様
♪～
～♪
砂の伝令よりの報告です
今回の任務で
砂隠れのチヨバア様１名が殉職
風影様は無事
帰還されたとのことです
ガイ班 カカシ班も無事任務終了
３日後には 木ノ葉に戻る予定です
そうか
なんとか うまくいったようだな
しかし これでよかったのでしょうか
どういう意味だ？
綱手様 １つだけ言わせてください
次回「風影の帰還」
（テマリ）
思い出写真館
（テマリ）我愛羅
（我愛羅）うん？
ちょっと懐かしい写真が
出てきたんだが見てみるかい？
おお どれどれ
こいつは木ノ葉で
中忍ちゅうにん試験をやったときの写真だな
（テマリ）
もう３年ぐらい前になるかな？
（カンクロウ）
こんときは我愛羅が暴走して
大変だったじゃん
（テマリ）
どうなることかと思ったけど
まさかあんなドタバタ忍者に
我愛羅が止められるとはね
（我愛羅）
うずまきナルトと木ノ葉隠れには
大きな借りができた
（テマリ）
まっ その木ノ葉とも今や同盟国
（カンクロウ）
音隠れとの戦いでは
助太刀にも行ったしな
（我愛羅）木ノ葉隠れと
今後もよい関係でいたいものだな
（カンクロウ）ところでテマリ
（テマリ）うん？
我愛羅の写真ばっかで
俺の写真が少な過ぎるじゃん
どうなってんだよ
ん～ まあ あの
出番の差っていうか
人気の差っていうか… ね
（カンクロウ）やっぱそうか…
（テマリ）すまん…